Guide to the Hewlett-Packard Company Ephemera Collection M1306
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hewlett-Packard Company ephemera collection
1957 - 1994
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M1306
1.5 Linear Feet (3 manuscript boxes)
This collection contains annual reports, sporadic issues of various Hewlett-Packard publications, product information flyers and brochures, and manuals for various Hewlett-Packard products.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
This collection contains annual reports, sporadic issues of various Hewlett-Packard publications, product information flyers and brochures, and manuals for various Hewlett-Packard products.
History
Bill Hewlett and Dave Packard were friends and fellow graduates of Stanford University. Following their graduation from Stanford, the two founded the electronics firm Hewlett-Packard Co. in 1938. Their first product - the resistance-capacity audio oscillator (HP 200A), an electronic instrument used to test sound equipment. The firm continued to produce electronic testing equipment, and expanded later into the realm of computers and their related peripherals, most notably desk top printers.
Acquisition Information
The materials in this collection originally formed part of the Silicon Valley Ephemera collection (M0443). Much of the material was donated by various donors.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Computer industry -- United States -- History; Microelectronics industry -- United States -- History.; Hewlett, William R.; Hewlett Packard Company; Packard, David, 1912-1996
- Publications, Series 1
  - Annual report, 1957 - 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual report, 1961 - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual report, 1965 - 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual report, 1969 - 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual report, 1973 - 1975 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual report, 1976 - 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual report, 1979 - 1980 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual report, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Hewlett-Packard Co.: Fifty years of looking to the future: calendar, 1989; (cy 1) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Hewlett-Packard Co.: Fifty years of looking to the future: calendar, 1989; (cy 2) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Hewlett-Packard in brief, 1 brochure (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hewlett-Packard journal, Vol. 36, 1985 Aug. - Nov. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hewlett-Packard journal, Vol. 37, 1986 Apr., June, July (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Hewlett-Packard journal, Vol. 38, 1987 Apr., Dec. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Hewlett-Packard journal, Vol. 39, 1988 Apr., Dec. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Hewlett-Packard journal, Vol. 40, 1989 Aug., Dec. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Hewlett-Packard journal, Vol. 41, 1991 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Hewlett-Packard journal, Vol. 45, 1994 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - HP direct, 1990 Summer/Fall (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Measure, 1988 - 1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Measure, 2000 May - June (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Scope and Contents note
    Note: final issue
  - Measurements, 1985 Nov. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Reporter, 1989 May / June (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Resolution, Vol. 1, no. 2 - Vol. 2, no. 2, 1994 - 1995 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Test and measurement news, 1989 - 1991 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Update, 1990 Apr. / May (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Applications and benefits of dual sensor power meters / Dave Martinez, 1984 Oct.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - The "art" of phase noise measurement / Dieter Scherer, 1985 Mar.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Curing a subtle but significant cause of noise figure error / Nicholas J. Kuhn, 1984 June; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - A designers guide to shielding / Tom Jerse, Mark Terrien, 1984 Aug.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Determining the measurement accuracy of the HP 8510 microwave network analyzer / Bruce Donecker, 1985 Mar.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Harmonic generation: using step recovery diodes and SRD modules. -- (Application Note, no. 920), undated; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Improved millimeter wave signal analysis / Frank David, 1983 Apr.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Let time domain response provide additional insight into network behavior / Doug Rytting, 1985 Mar.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Measuring phase noise and adjacent channel power with the 8901B modulation analyzer / Bob Burns, undated; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Mixer noise figure concerns and measurements / Ed Cantrell, 1985 Mar.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Scalar network analysis: an attractive and cost-effective technique for testing microwave components / Hugo Vifian, 1985 Mar.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Signal source characterization using low cost frequency and time counters / Dick Schneider, Lyle Hornback, undated; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - A survey of transistor noise characterization / by Nicolas J. Kuhn, 1984 Aug.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Techniques for measuring narrowband and broadband EMI signals using spectrum analyzers / Siegfried Linkwitz, Al Wilcox, 1984 June; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Wideband modulation analysis using vector demodulation techniques / Dana Kreitter, 1985 Mar.; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Wavelength: Microwave Measurement News, Vol. 3, no. 1, undated; Accession no. 2003-341 (Box 4)
  - Measure, 10-1963 - 01-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Measure, 02-1970 - 07-1971 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Measure, 08-1971 - 12-1972 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Measure, 01-1973 - 02-1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Measure, 04-1975 - 05-1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Measure, 08-1978 - 10-1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Watt's Current, 02-1956 - 07-1958 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Watt's Current, 10-1958 - 08-1960 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Watt's Current, 09-1960 - 03-1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Watt's Current, 04-1963 - 09-1967 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Watt's Current, 10-1967 - 12-1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Watt's Current, 01-1970 - 06-1971 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - HP Company Annual Reports, 1959 - 1988 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - Misc. Employee Communications (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - HP Local News, 10-1961 - 06-1963 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - The Peninsulan, 09-1971 - 01-1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Dynac News, Jan. - Mar., 1958 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - HP Shareholder Communications (Box 7, Folder 8)
- Product information, Series 2
  - Computers (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - DeskJet (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Contains miscellaneous flyers, brochures, advertizements, etc. for various Hewlett-Packard DeskJet printers.
  - Graphics gallery (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Contains miscellaneous flyers, brochures, advertizements, etc. for Graphics Gallery software.
  - LaserJet (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Contains miscellaneous flyers, brochures, advertizements, etc. for LaserJet printers and supplies.
  - QuickJet (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Contains miscellaneous flyers, brochures, advertizements, etc. for QuickJet printers and supplies.
  - ThinkJet (Box 2, Folder 20)
    Contains miscellaneous flyers, brochures, advertizements, etc. for ThinkJet printers and supplies.
  - Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Contains miscellaneous flyers, brochures, advertizements, etc. for various miscellaneous Hewlett-Packard products.
  - Miscellaneous product brochures and flyers, undated; Accession no. 2003-341; 4 items (Box 4)
    Contains miscellaneous flyers, brochures, advertizements, etc. for various Hewlett-Packard computer systems.
  - Misc. Promotional Materials (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Manuals, Series 3
  - ThinkJet personal printer owner's manual (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - ThinkJet: the personal printer from Hewlett-Packard reference manual (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - An easy course in using the HP-12C and other financial calculators / by Chris Coffin and Ted Wadman; illus. by Robert Bloch. -- Corvallis, Ore.: Grapevine Publications, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - An easy course in using the HP-28S / by John W. Loux and Chris Coffin; cover illus. by Robert Bloch. -- Corvallis, Ore.: Grapevine Publications, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - 400D/H/L vacuum tube voltmeter operating and service manual, 1959 Dec. 15; Accession no. 2003-341; 1 vol. (Box 4)
  - HP-IB isolated DAC power supply programmer model 59501B, 1983 Apr.; Accession no. 2003-341; 1 vol. (Box 4)
  - Introductory operating guide for the 59501A D/A power supply programmer with the HP 85 computer, 1982; Accession no. 2003-341; 1 vol. (Box 4)
- Catalogs, Series 4
  - Test & measurement catalog, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Test & measurement catalog, 1989; Accession no. 2003-341; 1 vol. (Box 4)
- Miscellaneous, Series 5
  - Invitation to dedication of "the garage" as a historical landmark, 1989 May 19 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Unrelated Promotional Materials (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Misc. HP Materials (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Clippings, Series 6
  - Clippings and articles (Box 3, Folder 4)